Gather round, come take a look...
It's time for Theatre of Darkness.
Rain or Shine
This is the story of a child who had just transferred,
to an elementary school in a certain rural town...
Haruko-san,
it's almost time for your footrace.
Um... Teacher?
What is it?
Wouldn't sports day
normally be canceled in heavy rain like this?
At this school,
since long ago,
the date for sports day has been set.
No matter how bad the weather is
it is never canceled.
Why is that?
Regardless of why,
that's just the rule.
Everyone acts like it's completely normal...
Is it strange that I'm the only one finding this weird?
I did it!
You came in 2nd place.
The kid from the Black Team took 1st.
The Black Team?
There's the Red Team, the White Team, and the Black Team, right?
No, there's no such thing as a Black Team.
Yes, the Black Team exists.
The winner of the beanbag toss is the Black Team!
The winner of the giant ball roll is the Black Team!
The winner of the relay race is also the Black Team!
What on earth is the Black Team...?
Whatever, who cares.
I'm soaking wet and covered in mud, I just want to go home.
Tug-of-war is next! Let's do our best, Haruko-chan!
Though the Black Team is gonna win anyway...
Listen up, everyone!
You must not lose to the Black Team in the tug-of-war!
Even if you lose,
do NOT let yourselves be pulled into the Black Team's territory!
Got it?!
Yes!
(Pulling hard)
Why?!
There's no one on the Black Team,
but we can't pull back at all!
(Pulling hard)
My feet are slipping!
What is this?!
(Pulling hard)
Haruko-chan, are you okay?
Huh?
Where are the kids from the Black Team?
The next event is starting. Let's go together!
Uh?
Yeah.
The next event is the Ominie-san 3-Legged Race!
Tomonari from Class 3-2
You were summoned by Teacher Yuriko.
Please come in front of the stand.
Do your best!
THE END
Black Team(Kuro-gumi): In Japanese schools, sports days typically divide students into only the Red Team (Aka-gumi) and the White Team (Shiro-gumi). The existence of an invisible/creepy Black Team is the anomaly of this episode.
Ominie-san: This is a macabre/mysterious recurring reference in the Yami Shibai universe (a ritualistic/sacrificial offering).